<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Your RSS Feed Title</title>
<description>A brief description of your RSS feed.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>http://yourwebsite.com/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="http://yourwebsite.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- LB -->

<item>
<title>The Blog is Live Lads!</title>
<guid>http://www.alexbarney.xyz/2019.html#the-blog-is-live-lads.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 20:26:36 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>
		After seemingly countless hours of pain, this thing is finally up and running. wew... Well now that this is taken care of I guess I will run down what you can probably expect me to be posting on here. I will most likely keep the topics programming/technology centric, however I may discuss other things as well if I feel like it (I don't really have much of a plan tbh). As far as tonight goes, I was planning to write up a synopsis about the video I posted this morning talking about how for a general use case, what programming language you write in doesn't really matter. I'm pretty gassed after setting this all up so I will save that for another time. Anyways, I will try to post updates here as often as I can.
</p>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>This Is A Blog</title>
<guid>http://www.alexbarney.xyz/2019.html#this-is-a-blog.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 09:59:49 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>
		So this is kind of a test blog post. Here is a list of things that I need to get working (btw if you are able to read this that means I did lol)
</p>
<ul>
		<li>
				Functional Rolling Blog Page
		</li>
		<li>
				RSS Feed
		</li>
		<li>
				Hope and pray that Apache doesn't ruin my life...
		</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
</item>




<item>
<title>Options +Indexes
test
Test Blog Post</title>
<guid>http://www.alexbarney.xyz/2019.html#</guid>
<pubDate>Options +IndexesThu, 07 Mar 2019 09:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[

]]></description>
</item>




<item>
<title>This is what a post looks like</title>
<guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#this-is-what-a-post-looks-like</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 14:38:38 -0700</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[
<h2 id='this-is-what-a-post-looks-like'>This is what a post looks like</h2><small>[<a aria-hidden="true" href="2018.html#this-is-what-a-post-looks-like">link</a>&mdash;<a href="blog/this-is-what-a-post-looks-like.html">standalone</a>]</small>

<p>This is autogenerated by the blog. As you can see, an equivalent RSS feed entry and standalone blog post is generated after you finalize the post.</p>
]]></description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>

